<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sahil hegde</title>
    <link>https://hegdesahil.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sahil hegde</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://hegdesahil.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>https://hegdesahil.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hegdesahil.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a fourth year Ph.D. student at UCLA working with Professor Steve Furlanetto. I am generally interested in building theory models to study anything happening in the early universe. I am currently using semi-analytic models to study the formation of the first stars and black holes in the universe &amp;mdash; see my &lt;a href=&#34;../research&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&gt;research page&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/spacerock-wide.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before coming to UCLA, I grew up in the San Francisco Bay Area and got my undergraduate degree in physics and math at Columbia University. While I was an undergrad, I spent summers with the Stanford Solar Physics Group, the Computational Physics Division at Los Alamos National Lab, and with a few groups at Columbia, working on projects ranging from solar physics to black hole accretion disk modeling &amp;mdash; all incorporating computational astrophysics in some form. If you&amp;rsquo;re really curious, take a peek at my &lt;a href=&#34;../files/hegde_cv_120324.pdf&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&gt;CV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>https://hegdesahil.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hegdesahil.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sahil@astro.ucla.edu&#34; &#xA;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;&gt;&lt;h2 align=&#39;center&#39;&gt;sahil [at] astro.ucla.edu&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>outreach</title>
      <link>https://hegdesahil.github.io/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hegdesahil.github.io/outreach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I also love to talk, teach, and write about astronomy. I help run the &lt;a href=&#34;https://planetarium.astro.ucla.edu&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; &#xA;&gt;UCLA planetarium&lt;/a&gt;, lead the &lt;a href=&#34;https://astro.ucla.edu/summer-observing-workshop.html&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; &#xA;&gt;Astronomy Live! Summer Observing Workshop&lt;/a&gt; for high school students in the LA area, and write articles with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://astrobites.org&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; &#xA;&gt;Astrobites&lt;/a&gt; collaboration, a graduate student-run organization that produces daily summaries of recently released astronomy papers. You can see the articles I&amp;rsquo;ve written for Astrobites &lt;a href=&#34;https://astrobites.org/author/shegde/&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; &#xA;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite parts of studying astronomy is the community &amp;ndash; I definitely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where I am now without the support of older, wiser students and faculty who supported me along the way. Now that I am older and (questionably!) wiser, I love to meet younger students and share my own experiences, so if you&amp;rsquo;d ever like to chat, please &lt;a href=&#34;../contact&#34; &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>research</title>
      <link>https://hegdesahil.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hegdesahil.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-stars&#34;&gt;first stars&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born from the pristine hydrogen gas of the early universe, the first generation of stars (also known as Population III, or Pop III, stars) are thought to have been very different from the stars we see today. In order to condense to high densities and form stars, clumps of gas need to radiate away their thermal energy (such that gravitational collapse can beat out the pressure support). In the local universe (for basically every star we&amp;rsquo;ve observed), this &amp;lsquo;cooling&amp;rsquo; of the gas is governed by the &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; elements produced by previous generations of stars. Pop III stars, however, are not so fortunate. In the early universe, the gas is too cold to excite hydrogen and cooling can therefore only occur inefficiently through molecular hydrogen, or H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. This results in stars thought to be tens to hundreds of times the mass of our Sun. At such large masses, they lived short, few million year lives, which, in some cases, ended in superluminous supernova explosions (SNe), releasing heavy elements and enriching their interstellar environments, setting the stage for more complex structures and later generations of stars to form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
